Madalyne Cross

Houston, TX 77096 madalyne.cross@gmail.com | 713-829-0084 <u>linkedin.com/in/madalyne-cross/</u> | <u>github.com/violanerd/react-portfolio</u>

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with a certificate from the Glasscock School of Continuing Studies at Rice University. A classically trained musician and experienced educator with strengths include breaking down complex tasks, attention to detail, passionate about learning and helping others achieve excellence.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Software Platforms/Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, MongoDB, GraphQL, Apollo, Github, Wordpress

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Rice University | May 2022 - November 2022 | Full Stack Development Bootcamp, Houston, TX

BirthdayPlanIt | GitHub URL | Deployed Application

- MERN Stack application where users can create an invitation to a birthday party, email guests an invite link and track RSVP's
- Collaboratively designed and built, implemented email feature with Nodemailer, integrated Apollo into React

Fam-Food-Finds | GitHub URL | Deployed Application

- Full stack application where users can share a review of a restaurant with family, collaboratively designed and developed
- Built with Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Sequelize, MySQL2, TailwindCSS, Javascript

Portfolio | GitHub URL | Deployed Portfolio

- React.js App to display portfolio projects
- Version built with HTML, CSS | <u>Deployed Portfolio</u>

Recipe-Box | GitHub URL | Deployed Application

- Collaborative team build of a Recipe-Box that allows users to save their favorite recipes, search for a recipe by ingredient, search by recipe name and get a random recipe.
 Implemented API functionality
- Built with Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Other Libraries/API's: Foundation CSS, JQuery, Edamam API, Punk API

Associate Dev-Ops Engineer | March 2022 - current | Cross Technology Resources, LLC., Houston, TX

- AWS, AWS-RDS, MS-SQL
- Current project is to build POC customer database on AWS-RDS instance from local

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Suzuki Violin/Viola Instructor | 2012 - 2022 | Pakachoag Music School, Powers School of Music, Wayland School of Music, Madalyne Cross Studio, MA | Upper Valley Music Center, NH

- Teach private and group lessons to 40+ students a week, 3 18 years old
- Create an encouraging learning environment developing skills of attention to detail, a high standard of excellence, focus, dedication, respect, resilience and teamwork
- Collaborate with Suzuki faculty for group classes, recitals, and special events

Director of the Massachusetts Suzuki Festival | August 2017 - May 2018 | Suzuki Association of Massachusetts, Boston, MA

- Hire faculty, recruit and register 200+ participants, process payments, manage budget
- Develop and implement scheduling tools in Excel, create and plan a two day event
- Provide excellent customer service

Administrative Secretary | November 2011 - August 2012 | The Hartt School Community Division, CT

- Provide excellent customer service via phone, email, and in person
- Process customer payments, handle cash, checks, and credit card information
- Schedule receptionists; develop and streamline front desk procedures

EDUCATION

Rice University Full Stack Certificate | Expected completion, November 2022 | Houston, TX

- Web Development: Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, MERN Stack, RESTFul APIs, MongoDB, GraphQL with Apollo

Masters of Music, Viola Performance with an emphasis in Suzuki Pedagogy from the University of Hartford | May 2012 | Hartford, CT

Bachelors of Music, Viola Performance from New York University | May 2008 | New York, NY

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Codecademy | 2022 | Online

- Learn Java, February 2022
- Build Basic Android Apps with Java, Expected completion November 2022

Introduction to Computer Science, Harvard Edx | Expected completion, November 2022 | Online

- Programming in C, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask, Java

Introduction to Computer Science in Python, Udacity | Expected completion November 2022 | Online

Python, build a web search engine